<bibdata type="standard" schema-version="v1.2.9">
  <fetched>2025-01-06</fetched>
  <title type="title-intro" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Geographic information</title>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Data quality</title>
  <title type="title-part" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Part 1: General requirements</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">Geographic information - Data quality - Part 1: General requirements</title>
  <title type="title-intro" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Information géographique</title>
  <title type="title-main" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Qualité des données</title>
  <title type="title-part" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Partie 1: Exigences générales</title>
  <title type="main" format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Information géographique - Qualité des données - Partie 1: Exigences générales</title>
  <uri type="src">https://www.iso.org/standard/78900.html</uri>
  <uri type="obp">https://www.iso.org/obp/ui/en/#!iso:std:78900:en</uri>
  <uri type="rss">https://www.iso.org/contents/data/standard/07/89/78900.detail.rss</uri>
  <docidentifier type="ISO" primary="true">ISO 19157-1:2023</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="iso-reference">ISO 19157-1:2023(E)</docidentifier>
  <docidentifier type="URN">urn:iso:std:iso:19157:-1:stage-60.60</docidentifier>
  <docnumber>19157</docnumber>
  <date type="published">
    <on>2023-04</on>
  </date>
  <contributor>
    <role type="publisher"/>
    <organization>
      <name>International Organization for Standardization</name>
      <abbreviation>ISO</abbreviation>
      <uri>www.iso.org</uri>
    </organization>
  </contributor>
  <edition>1</edition>
  <language>en</language>
  <language>fr</language>
  <script>Latn</script>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="en" script="Latn">This document establishes the principles for describing the quality of geographic data. It:
—    defines a well-considered system of components for describing data quality;
—    defines the process for defining additional, domain-specific components for describing data quality;
—    specifies components and the content structure of data quality measures;
—    describes general procedures for evaluating the quality of geographic data;
—    establishes principles for reporting data quality.
This document is applicable to data producers providing quality information to describe and assess how well a dataset conforms to its product specification and to data users attempting to determine whether or not specific geographic data are of sufficient quality for their particular application.
This document does not attempt to define minimum acceptable levels of quality for geographic data. Such information is usually present as a requirement in a data product specification, defined in accordance with ISO 19131, for example.</abstract>
  <abstract format="text/plain" language="fr" script="Latn">Le présent document établit les principes de description de la qualité des données géographiques. Il:
—    définit un système réfléchi de composants pour décrire la qualité des données;
—    établit le processus visant à définir des composants spécifiques à un domaine supplémentaires pour décrire la qualité des données;
—    spécifie les composants et la structure du contenu de mesures de la qualité des données;
—    décrit des procédures générales d’évaluation de la qualité des données géographiques;
—    établit les principes de rapportage de la qualité des données.
Le présent document s’applique aux producteurs de données fournissant des informations de qualité pour décrire et évaluer la façon dont un jeu de données répond à la spécification de contenu informationnel et aux utilisateurs cherchant à déterminer si des données géographiques spécifiques présentent ou non une qualité suffisante pour leur application particulière.
Le présent document n’a pas vocation à définir des niveaux minimums acceptables de qualité en matière de données géographiques. Ces informations sont généralement fournies sous forme d’exigences dans les spécifications de contenu informationnel, définies conformément à l’ISO 19131, par exemple.</abstract>
  <status>
    <stage>60</stage>
    <substage>60</substage>
  </status>
  <copyright>
    <from>2023</from>
    <owner>
      <organization>
        <name>ISO</name>
      </organization>
    </owner>
  </copyright>
  <relation type="obsoletes">
    <bibitem type="standard">
      <formattedref format="text/plain">ISO 19157:2013</formattedref>
      <docidentifier type="ISO" primary="true">ISO 19157:2013</docidentifier>
    </bibitem>
  </relation>
  <relation type="obsoletes">
    <bibitem type="standard">
      <formattedref format="text/plain">ISO 19157:2013/Amd 1:2018</formattedref>
      <docidentifier type="ISO" primary="true">ISO 19157:2013/Amd 1:2018</docidentifier>
    </bibitem>
  </relation>
  <place>Geneva</place>
</bibdata>